http://www.indiana.edu/privacy

HomePrivacy NoticePrivacy NoticeEffective: 2020-09-21ApplicabilityThis privacy notice applies only to the Indiana University Bloomington gateway (https://www.indiana.edu) and explains our practices concerning the collection, use, and disclosure of visitor information. Visitor information collected by Indiana University Bloomington will be used only as outlined in this privacy notice.Other units at the university may collect and use visitor information in different ways. Therefore, visitors to other university websites should review the privacy notices for the particular sites they visit. Indiana University Bloomington is not responsible for the content of other websites or for the privacy practices of websites outside the scope of this notice.ChangesBecause Internet technologies continue to evolve rapidly, Indiana University Bloomington may make appropriate changes to this notice in the future. Any such changes will be consistent with our commitment to respecting visitor privacy, and will be clearly posted in a revised privacy notice.Collection and UsePassive/Automatic CollectionWhen you view pages on our site, the web server automatically collects certain technical information from your computer and about your connection.This site is hosted on IU Sitehosting, a shared web-hosting environment provided by IU’s University Information Technology Services. For more information about privacy practices related to IU Sitehosting, read the IU Sitehosting Privacy Notice Supplement.In addition to any information collected by IU Sitehosting, our server and/or site collects the following:Your IP addressThe domain name from which you visit our siteUser-specific information on which pages are visitedAggregate information on pages visitedThe referring websiteThe date and time of visitThe duration of visitYour browser typeYour screen resolutionAggregate information collected by Google AnalyticsContinued use of our website indicates consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of this information as described in this notice.This technical information is retained in detail; it may not have a current retention/deletion schedule.Some technical information is retained in aggregate; it may not have a current retention/deletion schedule.Active/Manual/Voluntary CollectionOther than automatically collected technical information about your visit described above, or cookies and anonymous identifiers, described below, we may ask you to provide information voluntarily, such as through forms or other manual input—in order to make products and services available to you, to maintain and manage our relationship with you, including providing associated services, or to better understand and serve your needs. This information is generally shared and retained at IU as long as you continue to maintain a relationship with us. Your providing this information is wholly voluntary. However, not providing the requested information (or subsequently asking that the data be removed) may affect our ability to deliver the products or service for which the information is needed. Providing the requested information indicates your consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of this information as described in this notice. Information we may actively collect could include:The email addresses of those who post messages to our bulletin boardThe email addresses of those who communicate with us via emailThe email addresses of those who make postings to our chat areasNameAddressTelephone numberFax numberPayment information (e.g., credit card number and billing address)Information volunteered by the visitor, such as preferences, survey information, and/or site registrationsExpected year of high school graduationInformation UsageThis information is:Used for internal review and is then discardedUsed to improve the content of our siteUsed to customize the content of our siteUsed to notify visitors about updates to our siteUsed by us to contact visitors for marketing purposesInformation Used For ContactIf you supply us with your postal/mailing address:You may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events.If you do not wish to receive such mailings, or would like to be added to our “do not share” list, please let us know by:Sending us an email at the listed addressInformation SharingWe may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information with other entities or organizations.We do not share any personally identifiable information (PII) with other entities or organizations, except when legally required to do so, at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our website and applicable laws, or to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our website.Except as described above, we will not share any PII with any party for any reason.Except as provided in the Disclosure of Information section below, we do not attempt to use the technical information discussed in this section to identify individual visitors.Cookies and Anonymous IdentifiersA cookie is a small data file that is written to your hard drive that contains information about your visit to a web page. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may configure your browser not to accept them at all, or to notify and require approval before accepting new cookies. Some web pages/sites may not function properly if the cookies are turned off, or you may have to provide the same information each time you visit those pages.In order to customize the information and services offered to you, our site uses cookies to:Store visitors’ preferencesRecord session information, such as items that visitors add to their shopping cartRecord user-specific information on what pages users access or visitAlert visitors to new areas that we think might be of interest to them when they return to our siteRecord past activity at a site in order to provide better service when visitors return to our siteEnsure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner adsCustomize web page content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that visitors sendRecord aggregate information collected by Google AnalyticsAn anonymous identifier is a random string of characters that is used for the same purposes as a cookie on platforms, including certain mobile devices, where cookie technology is not available.ChildrenThis site is not directed to children under 13 years of age, does not sell products or services intended for purchase by children, and does not knowingly collect or store any personal information, even in aggregate, about children under the age of 13. We encourage parents and teachers to be involved in children’s Internet explorations. It is particularly important for parents to guide their children when they are asked to provide personal information online.Use of Third-party ServicesThis website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies (described above) to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including possibly your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google.For more information, please visit Google’s Privacy Policy.Additional Information Related to the Use of Third-party ServicesThis website utilizes Technolutions, Slate, a web analytics service. More information about this service can be found here: https://technolutions.com/privacy-policyThis website utilizes advertising services provided by BSMNT, an advertising agency contracted by IU Bloomington. For more information, please visit BSMNT’s Publisher and Platform Policies.Disclosure of InformationOther than sharing your information with other appropriate university personnel and units to ensure the quality, functionality, and security of our website, or manage your relationship with us, we will not disclose personally identifiable information about your use of the site except under the following circumstances:With your prior written (including email) consentWhen we have given you clear notice that we will disclose information that you voluntarily provideWith appropriate external parties, such as law enforcement agencies, in order to investigate and respond to suspected violations of law or university policy. Any such disclosures shall comply with all applicable laws and university policies.SecurityDue to the rapidly evolving nature of information technologies, no transmission of data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. While we are committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to university websites, and you do so at your own risk. However, once we receive your information, we will use reasonable safeguards consistent with prevailing industry standards and commensurate with the sensitivity of the data being stored to maintain the security of that information on our systems.In addition, we will comply with all applicable federal, state, and local laws regarding the privacy and security of visitor information.We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.Links to Non-university SitesIndiana University is not responsible for the availability, content, or privacy practices of non-university sites. Non-university sites are not bound by this site privacy notice policy and may or may not have their own privacy policies.Privacy Notice ChangesFrom time to time, we may use visitor information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice.Only data collected from the time of the policy change forward will be used for these new purposes. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our website periodically.Contact InformationIf you have questions or concerns about this policy, please contact us via email at studios@iu.edu.If you feel that this site is not following its stated policy and communicating with the owner of this site does not resolve the matter, or if you have general questions or concerns about privacy or information technology policy at Indiana University, please contact the chief privacy officer through the University Information Policy Office, 812-855-UIPO, privacy@iu.edu.
Indiana University Bloomington social media channels
Twitter
Facebook
Instagram
YouTube
Pinterest
LinkedIn
Contact, Address and Additional Links
